[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
General Ricardo Jacinto!
Are you done with the people
from Ginintuang Lupa?
Just because he stands
with the poor
doesn't mean he can paint
my father as the villain.
The Manila Telebalita reporter
is tearing my business apart.
You know what to do.
I won't mess this up,
General Jacinto.
Just scare him.
He thinks we shot the man
during the demolition.
The goal is to keep
that bastard's mouth shut.
I got the bike.
Rudy can finally
undergo surgery.
- [EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY]
- [RUDY GRUNTING]
Pa! Doc, help!
Doc, please do everything
to save my father!
Pa!
- Rudy!
- Pa! Pa!
- [AGENT] Hey.
- [RALLOS] What's up?
Hello. Tina, this is
for pick-up.
Courier's on the way.
Okay, sir.
Please log it here, sir.
- Thank you.
- Faster.
He's looking at us.
- Here's your ID, sir.
- Thank you.
Come on, let's go.
Hold it right there.
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
Yes, sir?
[BANGING LIGHTLY]
You forgot this.
- Oh!
- [BOTH GIGGLING]
Thank you, sir. He's so clumsy.
[GIGGLING]
- Let's go, you.
- [LAUGHS]
[LAUGHING] Silly me!
[GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [LAUGHS]
- Why did you leave it?
[REYES] Ma'am Sam. Here's
the paper for the bike.
[PAPER RUSTLING, THUDS]
It's stolen?
We called the owner
that it's registered under.
Said it was stolen last year.
And ma'am, his statements
match our records.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
Alright. We can still do
other things.
We'll find out who is behind
this group soon.
What a bummer.
That bike really drove me
to a corner.
Bike?
What kind of bike
are you talking about?
The bike of the man we met
at the bar.
We'd like to find out
who he is.
Sam.
I told you I'll take care
of that man.
Let me handle it.
That guy's my problem.
I don't need your help.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Uh-oh, a lovers' quarrel again?
Wait a second.
Do you have to be involved
with every thing I do?
Sam, why is your tone like that?
Is it because I got praised
and you got criticized?
Is that it?
What?
[SCOFFS] Excuse me?
Why would I be mad
when our co-teammates
get praised?
Shouldn't I be happy?
Can you please
just give me space.
Space? Are you
in a relationship?
[SEBASTIAN EXHALES HEAVILY]
Sam,
don't you see the effort
I'm putting in?
Huh?
Because if you do,
you won't treat me this way.
Did I ask for you to do this?
I didn't, did I?
You know, no matter what you do,
just don't. I can handle it
myself.
Alone.
- [KAREN] Space, space, space.
- [CHAIR CLATTERS]
There you go. Space, indeed.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Yes?
- [DOOR OPENS]
Sir.
Can I talk to you?
Of course.
Take a seat.
[CHAIR CLATTERS]
[LAUGHS AWKWARDLY]
Sir, to tell you the truth,
I feel really bad
for disappointing you.
I really want to make it up
to you but...
I just don't know how.
[LAUGHING] Sam,
don't be too harsh on yourself.
Everybody makes mistakes.
We all trip, we all fall.
It's part of the job.
[SAM] About the gold
smuggling case.
I really want us to close
that case
and to hold those
who are involved accountable.
Yes, I know. You are capable.
Sir, I just thought, what if we
form a small team?
Let's start with that.
So that from there,
we could know--
[PIA CLEARS THROAT]
Sorry.
The door was left open.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
I overheard your conversation
as well.
I'm utterly impressed, Jacinto.
Pia.
Sir.
[DELGADO] Hmm?
Are we trying to pull as many
strings as we can
here in the NCIA?
I'm just merely volunteering
to do something
that I know I'm capable
of solving.
Pia, Sam is perfectly capable.
Sir, with all due respect,
this one right here needs
to undergo retraining.
Has she already done that?
As far as I know, she hasn't.
Sir, I just realized.
If I were to complete
the retraining,
those groups might have already
come up with a plan against us!
The NCIA will still do its job.
Just not depending on you
this time.
Isn't that right,
Director Delgado?
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[INHALES SHARPLY]
You know, Sam,
Pia is right.
I order you not to dig into
the case any further.
I'll let a different agent
take care of it.
But sir, what about
the suspects?
[PIA] And we're still waiting...
for the committee's decision
on your suspension.
Right?
We'll surely catch them
but as of now,
while the committee is still
deciding on your case,
you're not allowed
to be involved.
Do you understand?
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[EKG MONITOR BEEPING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Doc, how's my father?
Is he safe now?
[DOCTOR] I'll be honest
with you.
Until the patient hasn't gone
under surgery,
- [SOBBING]
- his condition will worsen.
The next time this happens,
we might not be able
to save him any more.
It is time we're up against.
Excuse me.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SIGHS] Did you hear
what the doctor said, Gabo?
Time is running out
for your father.
To be able to save him,
to be able to have him
undergo an operation,
we need money.
[SOBBING CONTINUES]
Why? [CRYING]
Isn't Gabo doing
everything he can
to able to fund
his father's operation?
Why do you have to put
everything on his shoulder--
Who else are we depending on?!
No one's helping us anyway!
[BETCHAY SNIFFLES]
[VOICE BREAKING, SOBBING]
Well...
It's not like your father
expects anything of you either.
[BETCHAY SOBS]
Don't worry.
I'm not coming back here
without any money.
Gabo!
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
What's the news?
Lawin? Uwak?
We came back from NCIA.
We observed
and eavesdropped, Pops.
Positive, Pops.
A man caused a disturbance
when they were about
to arrest Tiger.
The man caught him first,
but he escaped
as soon as the NCIA arrived.
- It might be Gabo.
- Hmm.
He was about to catch Tiger.
The NCIA is also
looking for him.
They're checking on why
he's chasing Tiger.
Gabo's life has been
put in jeopardy.
Even the NCIA
wants to find him.
Pops.
Why don't you give Gabo
another chance?
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [CHEERING, LAUGHTER]
- [TEKLA] It's successful!
[DABOY] Guys, have some snack!
[OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
[TEKLA] Open it.
Why don't you do it?
Hey!
[WHOOPING]
Where's Gabo?
- Elton, grab a drink with us!
- [CHEERING]
- C'mon!
- Yeah!
Stop joking around.
You know what,
if I find out that you're
covering for Gabo,
I'll include you
in my police report.
- Hey!
- C'mon, Elton!
Relax, relax!
How could I?
Gabo owes me a huge debt!
Gabo won't let you down!
He did everything he could
to get that motorcycle back.
- Yes!
- He's right!
He has the motorcycle?
- Yes!
- Absolutely!
Relax, Elton!
He'll give it back.
You just have to trust him.
How could I trust him?
He seems so sketchy!
What's he doing?
Why did he use the motorcycle?
- It's a secret!
- A secret...
- ...tary! Secretary!
- A secretary!
- Yeah!
- His handwriting is beautiful.
Stop messing with me.
Just make sure
the motorcycle is with him!
Because if not,
I'll file a report against you.
[OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
[BETCHAY] This is
for patient Rudy Magtibay.
The one staying in the ICU.
This is for his surgery.
Here's the partial payment.
I'm sorry,
but this isn't enough for
the patient's initial payment.
Uh... ma'am...
Maybe you could allow
the surgery to happen?
I promise we'll pay!
Just please let
the surgery happen.
I'm sorry, ma'am, but
the hospital won't allow that.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAMENG] Oh.
Why the long face?
I went to the cashier.
I was about to pay
for Rudy's surgery.
But it's not enough.
Wait a minute, his surgery?
Where did you get the money?
Do you remember the girl
who came over?
- Yes.
- She said she wanted to help.
I asked for help.
She gave me money,
and I accepted it.
What?!
You talked to that woman?
She said she wanted to settle.
So I did.
Oh no.
You went to settle the agreement
all by yourself?
Gosh.
It's like you sold
your honor and your dignity.
What was I suppose to do?!
What's the point of any of that?
Rudy is dying!
We're talking about
someone's life here!
Honor and dignity are
completely worthless now.
Gabo is already working on
getting the money!
I believe he can do it!
That's enough.
I know he won't let Rudy die!
That's enough!
I already gave up on Gabo!
I hope I turn out wrong.
That's what I'm praying for.
I wish he could find a way
to save his father's life.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVS]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVS]
[ENGINE HUMMING,
TURNS OFF]
Gabo, what are you doing here?
Didn't we agree you
shouldn't come unless called?
Where's Tatang?
You've got some nerve showing
up here after screwing up.
I need Tatang, not you guys.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
Tatang!
Gabo, so you're here.
Where's Tatang?
What do you need, Gabo?
Mister Tomas, Mister Omeng,
I really need your help.
My father's in the hospital.
I need money.
You failed your first mission,
Gabo.
I know that.
But please give me
another chance.
Maybe you have another
mission for me.
There are plenty of missions
for you.
Like Pops said,
he chose you.
You know, Gabo,
you're very lucky.
Only a few passed
Pops's tests.
Don't let him down.
Come on, follow me.
[KAREN] We need a sketch
of what the guy looks like...
- [CLEARS THROAT]
- Ma'am Sam.
Why were you in
Sir Delgado's office?
I wanted to revisit
the gold smuggling case,
but Sir Delgado said no.
He told me to stay hands-off.
If Ma'am Pia's report
wasn't so sloppy,
we wouldn't be having
this problem.
Because this screw-up of mine
is embarrassing for my dad.
Imagine General Jacinto...
having an inefficient agent
for a daughter.
It's tough being in
your position.
Your hands are tied. You have
no choice but to give up.
[MUSIC BECOMES REFLECTIVE]
No. I won't give up
on this case.
Ma'am Sam, disobeying
Sir Delgado is dangerous.
If that's what it takes,
I'll do it.
To prove to NCIA that
I'm a good agent, I'll do it.
But I can't pull this off alone.
I still need your help.
Ma'am, your team is here
for you.
One for all.
All for one.
Yeah, because you can't
do this by yourself.
Thanks, guys.
But let's keep this from
Sir Delgado for now...
until we finish this case.
You know me.
I don't like having mistakes
on my record.
You know how I am.
Keep the line straight
and the plan detailed.
If a mistake was made...
it needs to be fixed.
[RESOLUTE MUSIC SWELLS]
[DOOR CLICKS]
You wanted to see me?
Have a seat.
Is there a problem?
I want to talk to you about Sam.
She's...
going through a lot right now.
She needs
her own support system.
I don't want
to see her so down.
And...
I don't want NCIA
to lose a great agent.
Yes.
I understand that you treat her
like your own daughter.
- I'm actually her best friend.
- [DELGADO] Hmm.
Hopefully, our operations
can go back to normal.
Don't mention this to her.
This might fall through.
I don't want
to give her false hope.
I have spoken
to the committee...
about canceling her suspension.
Really?
Thank you.
That's why, if you think
she has a problem
that I can help with,
let me know right away.
Yes, sir.
I'll do that.
You may leave.
Oh! [CHUCKLES]
Thank you, sir.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Ma'am Sam, what's the plan?
[KAREN CLEARS THROAT]
The one transacting
with Victor Zafra, Mr. Chan,
he will be our key to holding
Alias Tiger accountable.
Borromeo has already
gone there to scout.
You're right.
Once he speaks up,
the case against Zafra
will become much stronger.
However,
finding him won't be easy.
I'm sure
he is already in hiding.
He vanished into thin air.
[BORROMEO] Ma'am Sam.
I just came from Chinatown,
and I saw something.
A clearance sale poster
right at Mr. Chan's store.
Ah, pretty smart.
It's one of the oldest
tricks in the books.
He'll go into hiding,
and then after a while,
open the business again
under a different name.
We need to sell all this gold.
Give it all a discount.
Sell everything out!
Sir, why are we
selling it at a loss?
I'm going on a vacation.
I won't come back
for a long time.
And I need money!
More money!
Sell all the gold!
[CASTOR] That only means
one thing.
We need to start moving
before they do.
He's in a hurry
to get rid of all the gold.
[MONEY THUDS]
We have to act right now.
There is no other choice.
We need to set
the next stage in motion.
Let's just make sure that
Sir Delgado doesn't catch us.
Absolutely.
It's just us on this.
This case is a personal
matter for me.
I won't stop until Alias Tiger
is held accountable.
Especially those
who are working with him.
[LAO] Boss, we have
done what you ordered.
Show him, Lee.
[LEE] We've found
some information
about the NCIA agent
you're looking for.
[GLASS CLINKS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
What do you know about her?
Her name is Samantha Jacinto.
The youngest daughter
of the former NLEA Chief,
General Ricardo Jacinto,
and Beauty Queen,
Isobel Jacinto.
[LAO] She has a sister
who's a police officer,
Maxine Jacinto.
Well, it isn't hard to find her.
You can find everything
about her on the internet.
She arrested Victor.
We need to teach
her a lesson.
Lucas.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
Stop worrying about that.
We have a bigger problem.
What is it?
It's Mr. Chan.
I'm pretty sure they're going
to use Mr. Chan
as a witness against Victor.
We need to make sure
that he doesn't talk.
We'll take care of him.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
CONTINUES, FADES]
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
Whoever you are...
you clearly don't know
who you're messing with.
Get me out of here!
Once I get out of here,
I'll collect you myself!
I'll get you
and your whole family!
[SCREAMS]
[GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES, FADES]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[LINE RINGING]
[CELLPHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Hello? Ah, Mr. Chan!
Who is this?
[CHUCKLES] My name
is Carlota Diaz.
I went to your store
yesterday, remember?
Oh, yes.
Beautiful girl.
Why did you call?
I was hoping to buy some
jewelry from you for my store.
I need quite a lot of them.
You might have some
good designs available.
My budget is 5 million.
What made you decide to buy now?
[SAM] There's a festival
coming up in my province.
I thought about how
there are a lot of buyers there,
it would such a waste
of my potential earnings.
[MR. CHAN] I understand.
I'll give you
a big discount today.
There's a clearance sale.
I'll give you good-quality gold.
Alright.
Should I stop by your store?
[MR. CHAN] No, no.
Not in the store.
My store is closed today.
I'll meet you at the warehouse.
Okay? I'll text you the address.
All right, sir. See you.
Okay. I'll see you there.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Pops, Gabo is here.
- Tatang.
- Gabo!
I knew you'd come back.
I know you need my help
because your father
is in the hospital
and is fighting for his life.
You know, Gabo,
nothing escapes Pops.
He knows everything about you.
Because we keep tabs on you
24 hours a day.
We follow your every move
at all times.
We always have
eyes on you, Gabo.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Tatang, I would like
to make it up to you
because I really need your help.
Is there a mission
you can give me?
I have a mission for you.
When Victor Zafra was arrested
by the NCIA,
Mr. Chan was able to
snag the gold bars.
This is our chance to catch
the accomplice
of the gold-smuggling syndicate.
I called Mr. Chan.
He'll meet with me
to sell me gold.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Where can I find Mr. Chan?
You'll find him at a warehouse
in Plaza Mayor
on Cristobal Street.
[SAM] That's where he'll bring
the gold.
And that's where
we'll catch him.
After that, we'll bring him
to Sir Delgado.
[LAWIN] That's where he
does his transactions.
He's meeting a buyer tonight.
If you want to find him,
go there.
We'll make our move tonight.
I'll be needing your help.
You must take the gold
from Mr. Chan.
I don't care if he dies or not.
[ROBERT] They have eyes
and ears everywhere,
so we must be careful,
or they might intercept
our plan.
Because his transaction with
Victor Zafra was intercepted,
he doubled their men.
He knows he'll be the police's
next target.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GUNS COCKING]
[CLICKING]
With this, we can finally prove
that you're a great leader, Sam.
It will clear your name,
and your job won't be
at risk anymore.
Thank you very much,
everyone.
[PAPANG] You can do it, Gabo.
You've proven yourself to me
when we were in jail.
I know you won't let us down.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
This is the target.
A small-time reporter.
- Salvador.
- I won't fight back!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [GRUNTING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVS]
[LOUD THUDS]
This is Mr. Chan's calling card.
I'm here.
I think this is where
they're going.
They are acting without
my permission!
You want gold bars?
Go on a date with me.
Let's go to China!
Brace yourselves.
- Who's that?!
- Men, move in! Go!
Because the search...
Mr. Chan! We're being
attacked by the Zafras!
...will end in an
intense encounter.
- [SCREAMING]
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [GRUNTING]
[GUNSHOT]